(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-17T23:26:25.278831",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Once upon a time, there was a girl named Ina'nis.
She spent her days singing by the lake.
But one day,
She woke up somewhere else.
透き通る季節が好き
I love the crystal clear season,
風がまた熱を連れてくる
the wind brings warmth once again.
何千回も巡って
Cycling thousands of times,
何万回も輝く
shining tens of thousands of times,
そうやって光が生まれる
that's how light is born.
イノセント・ブルー ～ version de l'apprivoiser
[Innocent Blue ~ version de l'apprivoiser]
日差しが溶けてる
The sunlight is melting,
空の向こう どこまでも透明な青
beyond the sky, an endlessly transparent blue.
スピードを上げた
Picking up speed...
思い出たち
Memories
自分の意思で
By my own will
今飛び立つの
I take flight now
感じている
I can feel it
無邪気な誓い
An innocent vow
言葉はいらない
No words are needed
流れていく
Flowing away
水の行方に
Toward where the water goes
心を馳せよう
Let's let our thoughts wander
透き通る季節がすぎて
As the transparent season passes by
風がまた熱を連れてくる
The wind brings warmth once again
傷跡は消えていったわ
The scars have faded away
溢れだす情熱の交響曲
An overflowing symphony of passion
何千回も巡って
Cycling thousands of times
何万回も輝く
Shining tens of thousands of times
そうやって光が生まれる
That is how light is born
忘れじの言の葉
[Song Title: Unforgettable Words]
言の葉を紡いで
Weaving words together,
まどろんだ歌方
a slumbering, fleeting bubble.
旅人迷い込む
A traveler wanders into
おとぎの深霧
the deep fog of a fairytale.
差し伸べた手のひら
An outstretched palm,
そっと触れる予感
a softly touched premonition,
受け止めてこぼれた 光の一滴
a single drop of light caught and spilled over.
面影映ろうて
Traces of memories shifting,
追うだ幻
pursuing a phantom.
思いの果てる場所
The place where thoughts reach their end
まだ遥か遠くて
is still so far away.
求め探して彷徨って
Seeking, searching, and wandering,
やがて謡い戯れて
eventually singing and playing,
幾千幾万幾億の
thousands, tens of thousands, hundreds of millions
旋律となる
become a melody.
いつか失い奪われて
Even if lost and stolen someday,
消える定めでも
and destined to vanish,
それは忘れられることなく
it will never be forgotten,
物語
a story that remains.
指先を絡めて
Intertwining fingertips,
触れる誰かの夢
touching someone's dream.
小さ生まれた思いの
A small, newly born feeling,
木霊だけが響く
only its echo resonates.
言の葉を紡いで
Weaving words together,
まどろんだ歌方
a slumbering, fleeting bubble.
旅人の名前を
Calling the traveler's name
おとぎ話と言う
a fairytale.
求め探して彷徨って
Seeking, searching, and wandering,
やがて道となり
eventually becoming a path,
幾千幾万幾億の
where thousands, tens of thousands, hundreds of millions
英雄が行く
of heroes march on.
いつか失い奪われて
Even if lost and stolen someday,
さまよって
Wandering,
やがて戯れて
and eventually playing around,
幾千 佇むに 幾億の旋律となる
thousands standing become billions of melodies.
いつか失い 奪われて消える運命でも
Even if it's fated to be lost, stolen, and vanish someday,
それは忘れられることのない
it is a story
物語
that will never be forgotten.
ルルル...
Ru ru ru...
君の中にある赤と青き線
The red and blue lines inside you,
それらが結ばれるのは心の臓
where they connect is in your heart.
風の中でも負けないような声で
With a voice that won't lose even in the wind,
届ける言葉を今は育ててる
I am nurturing the words to deliver to you now.
時はまくらぎ
Time is a sleeper,
風はにきはだ
the wind is soft skin,
星はうぶすな
the stars are the birthland,
人はかげろう
and people are heat hazes.
なんで泣いてるの？と聞かれ答えれる
When asked "Why are you crying?", if I can answer
涙なんかじゃ
with tears, then it's nowhere near enough
僕ら出会えたことの意味にはまるで
to capture the full meaning of our meeting,
追いつかない
falling far short.
この身ひとつじゃ足りない叫び
A cry that a single body cannot hold.
君の手触れた時にだけ震えた
Only when touching your hand did my heart tremble,
心があったよ
revealing that it was truly there.
意味をいくつ越えれば僕らは辿り着けるのかな
How many meanings must we overcome to reach our destination?
愚かさでいい
Foolishness is fine,
醜さでいい
ugliness is fine,
正しさのその先で君と手を取りたい
beyond righteousness, I want to take your hand.
思い出せない大切な記憶
Precious memories I cannot recall,
言葉にならない
feelings here inside me
ここにある思い
that cannot be turned into words.
もしかしたら
What if...
what if...
それだけでこの心はできている
this heart is made of only that?
もしかしたら
What if...
what if...
君に気づいてと今もその胸を打ち鳴らす
it is still beating inside my chest, crying for you to notice?
なんで泣いてるの？と聞かれ答えれる
When asked "Why are you crying?", if I can answer
涙なんかじゃ
with tears, then it's nowhere near enough
僕ら出会えたことの意味にはまるで
to capture the full meaning of our meeting,
追いつかない
falling far short.
この身ひとつじゃ足りない叫び
A cry that a single body cannot hold.
君の手触れた時にだけ震えた
Only when touching your hand did my heart tremble,
心があったよ
revealing that it was truly there.
しさのその先で
...beyond righteousness,
君と生きてきた
I have lived together with you.
Wow! Hello, everyone!
Wah!
Good morning, afternoon, evening!
How are you guys doing?
Good, good.
Are you all miraculously preserve-- I can't talk.
Are you all miraculously preserved?
Yay! I can hear you guys.
Yeah, yeah, Ina wah wah wah wah!
Wah, hi! Good to see you, guys!
Welcome to my birthday live!
We made it in time this year. Let's go!
And of course, don't forget to...
...you know, talk about it, take screenshots, share with everyone...
...using the hashtag over here!
Yeah, so that I can also read what you guys have thought about while watching the stream and stuff.
And yeah, of course, you know, let us talk about... where are we? Where are we?
I just went through a door, and suddenly we ended up in this...
...I don't know, it almost looks like we're inside a storybook or something.
I have no idea where we are.
But you know what? We're gonna roll with it, 'cause that's what we do.
And of course, let us not forget... my clothes also changed! Look!
Do I look cute?
Aw, ta-da!
Wow! And of course, look at all the details! My flaps have gone longer.
I have this cool gauntlet now. Look at this!
Aw, I feel like a knight.
I feel like I can defeat all evil.
And of course I got my, I don't know, three glass pens behind me!
Wow, I wonder if this is my weapon.
I can poke people with my glass pens!
And all the details on the dress, isn't it beautiful?
And look! My skirt is actually made out of Takodachis.
Ooh! That's right.
And also I can already see it, you know, you guys are going, 'Oh, Ina, that's me! That's me!'
But yeah, look at this beautiful, beautiful outfit!
Of course, I gotta thank Kuroboshi-papa for designing this wonderful, wonderful outfit.
Thank you, Kuroboshi-papa!
You're always the best at making the outfits, so, yeah!
And you know, I wanna talk about a lot of things, but it is my birthday, and I'm gonna go have fun around here.
I don't know where we are, but you know, I'm gonna go look around and see where we end up.
We'll see, I don't know. Maybe we'll find something fun to do.
But yeah, you know, I guess I'll see you guys around. Take care!
Aw, what is this place? I don't know, do they have food around here?
あ
Ah.
え？ え？ あ、アキ先輩じゃないですか！
Huh? Huh? Ah, Aki-senpai!
あ！ イナ！ アキ先輩！
Ah! Ina! Aki-senpai!
イナー！ え？ なんで石になってたんですか？
Ina! Huh? Why were you turned to stone?
分かんない。なんか影があったような気がして、気づいたら固まってたけど...
I don't know. I felt like there was a shadow, and before I knew it, I was frozen...
ええー
Ehh?
イナ。 はい。 どこー？ ここは。
Ina. Yes? Where is this place?
私も知らないんです。
I don't know either.
イナも知らないの？！ はい！
Ina doesn't know either?! Nope!
なんか急にドアにギュッてしたら、衣装もこれになったし、ここどこ...
Suddenly, when I pushed through the door, my outfit became this, and I don't know where...
衣装も！
Your outfit too!
イナ、可愛いー！ 新衣装？ 新衣装ー！
Ina, you're so cute! New outfit? New outfit!
そうなんです！ 可愛いでしょう？
That's right! Isn't it cute?
めっちゃ可愛い！ よく見せて！ よく見せてよ！
Super cute! Show me! Show me better!
可愛い！ 可愛いー！
Cute! So cute!
いやー、でも、ここ、なんか全然知らない場所でアキ先輩がいて、なんか嬉しいー！
Hehe, but being in a totally unknown place with Aki-senpai here makes me so happy!
ほんとー？ そうー？
Really? Is that so?
ええ、アキロゼもね、3Dの姿でイナとこうやって会えて、の、実は...
Yeah, for Akiroze too, meeting Ina like this in 3D is actually...
嬉しい。
...really happy.
嬉しいー！ 実は私、アキ先輩といつか歌ったり踊ったりやりたかったんです！
So happy! Actually, I've always wanted to sing and dance with Aki-senpai someday!
えっ？ じゃあ、もし物理的に一緒に今日は歌えるの？
Eh? Wait, does that mean we get to sing together today?
いいんですか？ / ワーイ！ やったー！ 嬉しい！
Is that really okay? / Yay! We did it! I'm so happy!
どの曲が良いかな？
Which song should we do?
ふんふんふん、ホロライブの曲もあるしね、色々。
Hmm, well there are various Hololive songs too, right?
そうですね。でも、なんか先輩の曲の中で、一番一番好きな曲は... やっぱりあの曲ですね！
That's true. But out of all Senpai's songs, my absolute favorite song is... definitely that one!
え？ あれ？ / あれですね！
Eh? That one? / That one, right?
でも分かんないな、言ってくれないと。
Wait, I don't know unless you tell me!
あれですね！ アキ先輩の、こう...
It's that one, right? Aki-senpai's...
ちょっとセクシー... セクシーダンス？ セクシーダンスがいっぱいある... あ、いっぱいじゃないか（笑）
With that slightly sexy... sexy dance? There are lots of sexy dances... / Ah, wait, not lots (laughs).
でも、でも、なんかアキ先輩だったら、この曲ですね。
But still, if it's Aki-senpai, it has to be this song.
じゃあ、今日は一緒に『シャルイース』...
Then today, shall we sing "Shaluise" together?
いいんですかー？ / 歌おう、イナ！ / はーい！ よろしくお願いします！
Is it really okay? / Let's sing it, Ina! / Yay! Thank you so much!
嬉しい！ / 『シャルイース』...
I'm so happy! / "Shaluise"...
イナとこうやって歌うのもね、初めてだもんね。
Singing together like this with Ina is a first time for us, right?
そうですね。なんかライブとかあんまり機会がなくて... うん。
That's true. We haven't had many chances for lives or anything... Yeah.
確かに！ やっと、やっと、やっと！ 嬉しい！ 嬉しい！
That's for sure! Finally, finally, finally! I'm so happy!
じゃあ... / じゃあ！ / アキローゼの『シャルイース』は何と言っても... アキローゼの国の伝承歌...
Well then... / Well then! / Aki Rosenthal's "Shaluise" is, above all, the traditional folk song of Aki Rosenthal's homeland...
だから何かね、イナの助けになることがあるかもしれないし、一緒に歌ってパワーをね、分けてもらいたいなと思うから...
So I thought maybe it could be of some help to Ina, and by singing together, we could share some power...
頑張ろう！ / はい！ じゃあよろしくお願いします！
Let's do our best! / Yes! I look forward to working with you!
あー、ドキドキする！ / はい！ じゃあ、行きましょうか！
Ah, my heart is pounding! / Yes! Well then, shall we go?
じゃあこっちこっちこっち...
This way, this way, this way!
よし！ じゃあ、頑張るぞ！ / はい！
Alright, let me do my best! / Yes!
Kontas harelia on shaluise, alimita po ti mai julik
Seklaks oknok restina kating, hapua myukil shalube iru
Yai tili leo minas sakchu, diga nawe minasu riga
Nesi linas wena vetikas, timi horas morofua afua
Kontas harelia on shaluise, alimita po ti mai jrik
Aru wia tulus julia, don tokia stulia
Kontas harelia on shaluise, alimita po ti mai julik
Seklaks oknok restina kating, hapua myukil shalube iru
E tudari kari biria, faratos lumia dis lamo
Kuruswini yaminai jurik, manelas mukuru
Tiri daru pipuru, no tamuru, farmai mirare mamsu sefuri
Ono maboru maniro, undarune, rina wia sarame, te kanto miralira
hau wi ra si mi ya
fi mo ra sya ro ni ko nya
i mi o i fo ne o na
fi mo ra sya ro ra
kon tos a re ri a o sya ru miis
a mi nu mi ta fo fi ma i ju ri
zi guk o no ku re si no kei zin
a fo a ryu ki ru sya ru be i ru
ma ryu te sa
mo ra te kan
i mi ho i nya s mo ro fu...
あ... ふ... あ...
Ah... fu... ah...
クロイウタ
[Title: Kuroi Uta / Dark Song]
荒だたせり
Agitating and roughing,
破滅へと
towards destruction.
獣となりときり
Becoming a beast and severing,
奪い去る
snatching away
晴れの調べ
the melody of clear skies.
輪廻の糸垂り
The thread of reincarnation hanging down,
じっと羽ばたく雨
the rain quietly flapping its wings,
濃い暗い白から
from the deep, dark white.
いつ終わるとつき 声甘く記録羽
When will it end? The sweet voice, recorded feathers...
ささめく
Whispering,
黒い花 あの声が
the black flower... that voice...
壊れた目の
With broken eyes,
あるまま
remaining as it is...
黒い花 あの歌が
The black flower... that song...
つくりまいつ
endlessly spinning,
あるまま
remaining as it is...
意味
Meaning...
あたらせり 氷合う歌
A song of meeting ice...
悪夢なまう ひう
Nightmares dance and cry...
霧立ち切る詩が 幾紅い森から
A song cutting through the fog from crimson forests...
いぬべく穢れあらむ 弱いあの想い
Fleeting impurities, those fragile feelings...
あがれる黒い羽
Soaring black wings...
あの声が
That voice...
祈りの命が
The life of prayers...
あるまま
As it is...
黒い羽
Black wings...
あの歌が
That song...
懺悔の日が
The day of repentance...
あるまま 祈れ
As it is, pray...
最悪は 街を降りる
The worst descends upon the town.
壊れた時 人 夢
Broken time, people, dreams...
振り返り
Looking back...
別れゆき 許されざる音
Parting ways, an unforgiven sound...
花散る
Petals scatter...
秘密の黄昏に 君の手をとった
In secret twilight, I took your hand.
古のバラード 繰り返すように紡ぐ
Weaving as if repeating an ancient ballad.
君のことをいつも歌いたい
I always want to sing of you.
悲しい夜を温もりで満たして
Filling the sad night with warmth,
愛を見つけて
finding love.
ヒナギクが咲いてた 白い月輝いてた
Daisies were blooming, the white moon shining.
君のささやきで始まるよ とこしえのstoria
It begins with your whisper—an eternal storia.
storia...
風が消した storia
The wind erased storia
水の中
In the water,
沈んで行く
sinking down,
懐かしい
a nostalgic...
恋の物語
...love story.
光と影の中から
From within the light and shadow,
愛しさは生まれて
affection was born,
還る
and returns.
君と見た
With you...
君の目を見ていた
I looked into your eyes.
万有の愛しさびとを
All beloved ones,
その腕の中で
in those arms.
恋人のささやき
Whispers of lovers,
星くずの下
beneath the stardust,
古のバラード
an ancient ballad.
泉を満たして
Filling the spring,
風は西へ
the wind goes to the west.
優しい歌を君と歌いたい
I want to sing a gentle song with you.
五月の月が今ここにある
The May moon is now right here.
恋の歌が
As the love song...
今夜響くから
...reverberates tonight,
冷たい胸を
fill your cold chest...
温もりで満たして
...with warmth.
語ろう
Let us tell...
愛の storia
...the storia of love.
あれ？ 大丈夫？
Huh? Are you okay?
大丈夫...ですか？
Are you... okay?
あれ？ 動ける！ 動けるぞ！
Huh? We can move! We can move!
やったー！ やったー！
Yay! We did it!
動けるってなったね！
We can move now!
いつものやつだ！
It's the usual trick!
動ける、動ける！ よかった～！
We can move, we can move! Thank goodness!
イナちゃんが助けてくれたやつ？
Is this what Ina-chan saved us with?
なんとかぴょんしたら、動けるようになってよかった！
When I jumped around, you became able to move! I'm so glad!
よかったー！ よかったー！
Thank goodness! Thank goodness!
なんで石になってたんですか？
Why were you turned into stone?
なんでだっけ？
Why was it again?
なんか見たよね？
We saw something, right?
なんかいた... なんかいたんだよね。
Something was there... There was something, right?
翼が生えてたかな...
Did it have wings?
なんか、龍っぽかったかな？
Like... was it dragon-like?
龍？ ドラゴン？
A dragon?
龍っぽかった気がするけど... なんか...
I feel like it was dragon-like, but... somehow...
わっかんねえ！
I have no idea!
ごめんごめん！ 覚えてないけど...
Sorry, sorry! We don't really remember, but...
あ、そういえば！
Ah, speaking of which!
イナちゃん！
Ina-chan!
お誕生日じゃない？
Isn't it your birthday?
そうです！ お誕生日です！
That's right! It's my birthday!
おめでとー！
Happy birthday!
いや、大好きな二人と一緒って嬉しー！
I'm so happy to be here with two people I love so much!
照れるー！ 嬉しいー！
You're making us blush! We're so happy!
イナちゃんと5期生は、デビューも近かったもんね。
Ina-chan and us 5th gen debuted around the same time, after all.
そうですね、1ヶ月くらいだったから、もう同期...
Right, it was only about a month apart, so it almost feels like we're classmates...
同期みたいな感じだから、嬉しい！
Since it feels like we're in the same gen, I'm so happy!
そうですね。でも、ししろんと歌う機会があまりなくて...
That's right. But I didn't have many chances to sing with Shishiron...
なかったから... 今回なんか...
Yeah, since we didn't... So this time...
いつか、わため先輩とししろんと歌いたいなって...
I always wanted to sing with Watame-senpai and Shishiron someday...
嬉しい！ めっちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so happy! Super happy!
二人の歌声がめちゃくちゃ大、大、大好きなので、嬉しい！
I love both of your singing voices so, so much, so I'm really happy!
ありがとう！ みんな大、大、大好きだよ！
Thank you! I love both of you so, so much!
私の方が好きだから！
I love you more!
いやいや、わための方が...
No no, Watame loves her more...
やめて！ ケンカしないで！ どっちが好きなの？
Stop! Don't fight! Which one do you like more?
好きなんだよなぁ
I really love this...
助け... 助けて！
Help... Help me!
あ、でもイナちゃん、なんか服が可愛くなってる！
Ah, but Ina-chan, your outfit looks so cute!
そうですね、なんか... ドアがあって...
Yeah, like... there was a door...
ドアをぴょんと、ぴょんとしたら、この衣装になりました！
I hopped right through it, and ended up in this outfit!
かわいい！似合ってる！
So cute! It really suits you!
よく見たらさ、Takodachi...
If you look closely... Takodachi...
Takodachiがいっぱい居るんだよね、これ。
There are so many Takodachis on it!
靴もTakodachi！
Even the shoes are Takodachis!
そう、Takodachiなの可愛くない？
Right? Isn't it cute how they're Takodachis?
おしゃれだね！ねー、いいなー！
That's so stylish! Yeah, I'm jealous~
いや、でも... 嬉しい、この...
Ah, but... I'm so happy, this...
う〜！あっという間！意味分かんない、嬉しい！
Wow~! It went by in a flash! It feels unreal, I'm so happy!
こちらこそだよ！あ、わため...
Likewise! Ah, Watame...
え、あなたちょっと時間があるんじゃないの？
Wait, don't you have somewhere you need to be soon?
え、もう時間？やばい、やばい！
Wait, is it already time? Oh no, oh no!
もう行かないと、行かないと！
I gotta go, I gotta go!
Havernightの収録、あなたあるんじゃないの？
Don't you have a recording for Havernight?
やばい！飛行機乗れない、飛行機乗っていかないと！
Oh no! I'll miss my flight, I have to go catch my plane!
じゃあまたね！みんなありがとう！バイバイ！
See you later then! Thank you everyone! Bye-bye!
なんか、なんか居るぞ？なんだあれ？
Wait, there's something over there? What's that?
急げ、急げ！あ、急がないと！
Hurry, hurry! Ah, I gotta hurry too!
That was so fun! I got to finally sing with Shiro and of course with Watame-senpai. I'm so, so happy, you know?
Huh, did they say they saw something like a dragon? A dragon?
Well, after all the singing and dancing, I'm kind of... kind of getting sleepy. So I'm just... gonna take a small nap, okay? I'm gonna take a small nap, so...
Okay... Yeah, I'll just go... go...
『とある竜の恋の歌』
[Title: Song of a Certain Dragon's Love]
音の無き大地に 恋の歌 響けば
When a song of love echoes across the silent earth,
狂い出す 歯車 止められぬ 宿命が はじけた
The gears turn wild, and an unstoppable destiny bursts forth.
よみがえる 今 いにしえより
Reawakening now, from ancient times,
継ぐ 記憶の 恋 目覚めた
the memories passed down... love has reawakened.
絆を 求めて 炎は ほとばしる
Seeking a bond, the flames gush forth.
儚い 歳月 気高き 君の 呪縛
Fleeting years, the noble spell of yours...
透き通る 魂 嘘もなく 気高く
A transparent soul, noble and free of lies,
原罪を 抱えて 未熟な 恋を 生む 愚かさ
Carrying original sin, giving birth to an immature love—a foolishness.
月明かり 今 二人を 照らす
The moonlight now shines upon us two,
幾重にも 束ねた 刻 重ねた
Layers upon layers bound together, time stacked upon time.
絆の 行方を 両手で 抱きしめた
I embraced the destination of our bond with both hands.
終わりと 始まり 尊き 君の 記憶
The end and the beginning, your precious memories.
絆を求めて
Seeking a bond,
炎はほとばしる
flames burst forth.
儚い財より
More than fleeting treasures,
けだかき君の呪縛
the noble curse of yours.
絆の行方を
The whereabouts of our bond,
両手で抱きしめた
I embraced with both hands.
終わりと始まり
The end and the beginning,
尊き君の記憶
your precious memories.
Injakonasute
Injakonera
Injakonasa
Injakonasu
Injakonapa
Injakonakasa
Injakonaho
カイネ／救済
[Title: Kainé / Salvation]
Shul parel moihim
Ar, jaruk noisin
Dah galach dalfouir
Malech foir dir azlad erenj boir
Hiuo tantiera hadreikun harech falale ya boi
Hiuo migenda yakachren nohei kaine rekara
Hiuo migenda ya kochren nohei
Hiuo mo
Tei koimiren tara bairatru
Shul parel moihim
Ar, jaruk noisin
Dah galach dalfouir
Malech foir dir azlad erenj boir
Hiuo tantiera hadreikun harech falale ya boi
Hiuo migenda yakachren nohei kaine rekara
Hiuo mo
Tei koimiren tara bairatru
時の揺りかごで
In the cradle of time,
冷たい夢を見る
I dream a cold dream.
君が歌ってくれた 優しい 優しい子守歌
The gentle, gentle lullaby you sang to me...
君が望んだのは... 終わらぬ世界
What you desired... was an endless world.
俺が望むのは... 世界の終わり
What I desired... was the end of the world.
選ばれし声は 迷い 憂い 悼み
The chosen voice, in hesitation, sorrow, and grief,
歌う 悲しみを 喜びに
Sings, turning sadness into joy,
苦しみを 悦びに変えて
and suffering into pleasure.
報われずに 君は朽ちていくの？
Unrewarded, will you rot away?
共に佇む この世界から 君だけを
From this world we stand in together, only you...
未来は 交わらない
Our futures shall never intersect.
巡り巡る 命の世界に / この手で
In the ever-revolving world of life... / With these hands...
安らぎと 救いを与えて / 終わらせたい
Granting peace and salvation... / I want to end it.
届かない 届かない 祈りは 虚しさだけを残して
Unreachable prayers leave behind only emptiness,
始まる...
It begins...
楽園は 壊れて
Paradise is broken,
幸せすらも 願わない 定めを 逃れて
Escaping a fate that doesn't even wish for happiness,
君が望んだのは... あなたの未来
What you desired... was your future.
俺が望んだのは... 訪れる日を 追い求め続けたのは
What I desired... what I kept chasing after day after day...
優しい 笑顔 それだけなのに...
Was just a gentle smile, and yet...
終わらない 絶望を / 歌声を
Endless despair... / A singing voice...
希望に変えて / 叫び続けたい
Turns into hope... / I want to keep screaming!
滅びる定めなら / 惜しみなく
If it's a fate destined for destruction... / Without regret...
捧げたい / 弔いの歌よ 響け
I want to dedicate it all! / Echo, song of mourning!
巡り巡る 世界に 安らぎと 祝福を
Peace and blessings unto the ever-revolving world,
光を 定めを 闇を 放ち
Releasing the light, fate, and darkness,
絶望を 歌声を 希望に変えて 叫び続け
Turning despair and singing into hope, keeping screaming,
君は分かち合っていくの？
Will you share in this together?
弔いの歌よ 響け
Echo, song of mourning!
君が望んだのは... 俺が望んだのは...
What you desired... What I desired...
残された声は 嘆き 君を思いながら
The remaining voice, in lamentation, thinking of you,
ひとり 君のために歌う
Sings alone for your sake.
ひとり 君のために...
Alone, for your sake...
巡り巡る 世界に この手で 安らぎと 祝福を
In the ever-revolving world, with these hands, granting peace and blessings,
終わらせたい この身は 君となら どこまでも
I want to end it; if I am with you, I will go anywhere.
遥か遠く 照らして 永遠に続くレクイエム
Illuminating the far distance, an eternal requiem,
光を 定めを 闇を 放ち
Releasing the light, fate, and darkness,
光の底に 眠れ
Sleep at the bottom of the light.
Bae, are you okay?
My knight!
Finally you've come! Seriously, I waited like a hundred years, man. What took you so long?
Hundred, hundred years?!
A hundred, hundred years?!
Yeah. Wait, hold on, hold on.
How... Google, how long does a rat live?
Man, all my... all my muscles... oh, they're so rigid from being stuck as a statue, but thank you so much for saving me!
Man, all my muscles... they're so rigid from being stuck as a statue, but thank you so much for saving me!
Don't worry. You know, Ina... Ina-nest the hero is here to save you.
Oh, thank you!
Yeah, we defeated the evil dragon.
Served 'em right!
I don't know if you guys saw, but there was an evil dragon...
Yeah! How dare they.
Are you... Are you okay? Are you okay?
I'm okay, I'm okay! I'm good, thank you.
Yeah, now that you're all well, you might as well... say the thing.
Eh?
Say... say the thing. You know, the thing! The thing. -What thing?
You know, like today is a special day...
Oh! Yeah, today is... um... today is the day that the princess has been saved!
Thank you very much! Thank you! 拍手、拍手、はい！ あざます、あざます！
Thank you very much! Thank you! Round of applause! Thanks!
No, no, no, Bae, Bae, Bae...
Do you know what day it is when... this purple one become to be?
Oh! I see, you're looking for that one?
Yeah, yeah, okay, okay, okay.
Ina-chan! Happy Birthday!
Yay! Thanks for joining me today, Bae!
Thanks for inviting me! I'm so happy! It was so fun! Oh yeah, so fun!
To dance with you, sing with you, it's the best! It's the best.
Yes, I just wanted to say, I know your new outfit is so cute.
Thank you! You like it?
It's so cute, oh my god.
It's... it's called...
What's the outfit called?
勇者！
Hero!
勇者 Ina! Oh!
Hero Ina! Oh!
That's right! I look like a hero, right?
You do look like a hero! My hero!
Ooh~
Ah, Bae! And Mr. Squeaks, thanks for leading me to Bae!
Thanks, man! You did great! High five!
Man, if it wasn't for him, I'd be stuck as a statue forever.
Don't shake your head too much, it's gonna fall off.
Yeah, she's used to it.
Oh no! There we go, it's all good.
But yeah, thank you, Bae, for joining, for saving me!
Well, I think... are you still going on a journey? You're continuing your journey after this?
Yes! I am a hero after all! I gotta go see all the princesses I gotta save.
Excuse me? Huh? It wasn't just me?!
All right, let's go! Bye-bye!
Well, that's that. On to the next princess! Let's go!
[勇者 / Lyrics, Music: Ayase]
[Title: The Hero / Lyrics, Music: Ayase]
No more pages left in that story
Our hero goes into slumber deep
Leaving behind a veil of peace for all
Saving the fallen world
The flow of time erases without mercy
Any trace of memories and news
Even the traces left in life for now
Rusting as time moves
And yet I keep all your hopes
All the words and wishes
Courageous ones still dwell inside me
And even now in my heart keep living through
On a city street sharing the same path
And nothing more to do that line
Should have been, but suddenly I was wondering
All those tears rolling down my cheeks
Why did they come out?
And for I want to find out until right now
If I imagine the journey we walked about again
Though I am no longer walking next to you
One day I know I'll find the truth
From the ending starts a new story
Pass through a place from this journey
Strolling on a distant goal forever, ever, ever, ever as now
Another story unfolds into
A journey that alone I set out to
In the local talk of every town I stop in
They are all recalling the person that you were
Unwavering kindness
Is spoken of you, acting all cool
In everything you do
Here and there we can find scattered symbols around
Many-sized things that all we won't forget
And even that
Was for me so one day I wouldn't find myself
Alone, becoming lonely
And I call to mind every moment of our journey
When I see the smiles
Left in these scenes
Many days ended in fairytale scenes
That arose at the end for we have seen
And at that moment, our fate call me
Taking 100% of the journey start with me
Even if your courage is swept away to the distance
And though in a trace, you'm what everybody can recall
I will bring you along with me into the future shine
And though it all began right at that time
Mundane everyday signs, the moments ignited in laughter
As you remain, by reflections of those times
Go on as brightly shining
...bright and dull days, we will rise out,
looking back and still standing tall, proud,
evermore gently,
staring right at me without a sound,
I'm perceiving you around.
Now, for you, I'm starting this journey,
searching for the end of the hero,
forever, ever, ever, as you know.
Now, only the beginning has come to be an end,
and those that you protected and kept in safety,
these budding lives are with me on this journey...
Yay!
And then they lived happily ever after...
or should I say, Evermore.
Well, yeah! Thank you guys for watching today.
I hope you guys enjoyed it. Make sure you, you know, tell me how it was using the hashtag.
And of course, since it is my birthday, I also have to introduce all of my birthday merch to you guys!
Yay!
So we have these items for the birthday merch this year. Let's see...
Tada!
Yay! Look, this is my 2025 birthday merch.
Uh, we have a couple of items, so the first item... Next!
Okay, with the first item we have the Reversible Tote Bag. It has a different design on each side,
so depending on what you feel like having on the outside, you can choose between...
the lovely, lovely key visual by chibi-sensei or a very simplified design to be more incognito.
And of course, we have another one. So, next!
We have the Takogame! Shaker Acrylic Keychain.
This one I designed myself, and I wanted to kind of like, you know, you can carry it around and it kind of seems like...
a little game that you can play and you can shake it around and the Takodachis will shake. It's a really fun item.
And then next we also have the Takodachi Cable Tie,
where you can organize the messy, messy chaos that is the cables in your bag, like me.
But yeah, I hope they're useful.
And last but not least, we have the... Next!
Mini "Ina the Hero" Plushie Keychain, a.k.a. Ninomae Ina'nis the Hero. This outfit, I call myself the hero.
It's a little cute plushie keychain that you can carry around everywhere, and I will protect you. It's like a lucky charm.
And of course, there is a full set bonus which is going to be a limited...
Or, we will have a limited edition postcard,
but if you buy the set, you also get the postcard. There's a limited set and a non-limited set, so there's that.
And of course, we also have a special hololive...
TCG card with the key art. It's like a thank you bonus for the complete set of the merch.
You know, this card will only be given to customers who purchase the hololive production...
oh, purchased from the hololive production Official Shop. And this is a...
Oshi Holomen card, which you can use... only one in the game.
I know there's a whole bunch of rules that you can check out on the website.
Unfortunately, it's only the Japanese version. There's only Japanese text on it, but...
you know, it's kind of like a special limited thing, so...
something nice to have.
But yeah! That is it for merch announcements, etc.
I hope you guys enjoyed the live today.
And of course, we still have the omake, the little NG kind of snippets in the end and the credits,
so please look forward to that!
Until next time, thank you again, everyone!
Have a wonderful rest of the morning, afternoon, or evening.
I'll see you guys later.
Bye-bye!
Thanks for watching everyone!!
I'm really happy that I was able to share this special day with you today!
Did you enjoy the live? Do you like the new outfit?? hehe
Just like the theme of the outfit, I would like to continue to do my bestest with everything I do!
...because that is what a hero... yuusha would do! >w< Thank you for cheering for me! always!!
I really wouldn't be here without all your support!!
And of course, BIG thank you to all the staff & creators that could make this happen too!!
I am always indebted to everyone's passion! THANK YOU THANK YOU & THANK YOU!